The Great Rock 'n' Roll Swindle is a comedy,
documentary, music film directed by Julien Temple.
A rather incoherent post-breakup Sex Pistols "documentary", told from the point of view of Pistols manager Malcolm McLaren, whose (arguable) position is
that the Sex Pistols in particular and punk rock in general were an elaborate scam perpetrated by him in order to make "a million pounds."
The Embezzler, played by Malcolm McLaren.
The Crook, played by Steve Jones.
The Tea-Maker, played by Paul Cook.
The Gimmick, played by Sid Vicious.
The Collaborator, played by John Lydon.
Helen, played by Helen Wellington-Lloyd.
The Great Rock 'n' Roll Swindle, also known as The Great Rock and Roll Swindle, is a 1980 British
mockumentary film directed by Julien Temple and produced by Don Boyd and Jeremy Thomas.
It centres on the British punk rock band Sex Pistols and, most
prominently, their manager Malcolm McLaren.
The tone is lighthearted.